A Guide to the Lunenburg County (Va.) Wills, 1743-1928
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Lunenburg County (Va.) Wills, 1743-1928
The Library of Virginia
1012167-1012168, 1175966-1175967, 1177153-1177168, 1177656-1177664
13.00 cu. ft. (29 boxes)
Lunenburg County (Va.) Circuit Court.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
These items came to the Library of Virginia in transfer of court papers from Lunenburg County under the accession number 42852.
Historical Information
Lunenburg County was formed in 1745 from Brunswick County. Part of Charlotte County was added in 1777.
Individuals dying with a written will died testate. After the death of an individual, his or her will was brought into court, where two of the subscribing witnesses swore that the document was genuine. After the will was proved, the executor was bonded to carry out his or her duties to settle the estate. The court then ordered the will to be recorded.
Scope and Content
Lunenburg County (Va.) Wills, 1743-1928, record the deceased's plan for how his or her estate was to be divided among his or her heirs following his or her death. Information commonly recorded in wills include the name of the deceased, also referred as the testator; names of heirs; a listing of real and personal property (including slaves) and how it was to be divided among the heirs; names of individuals who were to be the will's executors; the date will was written; and the date will was recorded at the court house.
Additional record types found in this collection include fiduciary records (inventories and accounts) and marriage lists. They were recorded in the Lunenburg County will books from 1760 to 1851. The collection also includes wills not recorded in will books.
Arrangement
Organized by date recorded in will books.
Adjunct Descriptive Data
Related Material
Lunenburg County Will Books can be found on microfilm at The Library of Virginia web site. Consult A Guide to Virginia County and City Records on Microfilm
Index Terms
Corporate Names:
Lunenburg County (Va.) Circuit Court.
Subjects:
African Americans -- History.; Estates (Law) -- Virginia -- Lunenburg County.; Land subdivision -- Virginia -- Lunenburg County.; Slaveholders -- Virginia -- Lunenburg County.; Slaves -- Virginia -- Lunenburg County.
Geographical Names:
Lunenburg County -- History.
Genre and Form Terms:
Estate inventories -- Virginia -- Lunenburg County.; Fiduciary records -- Virginia -- Lunenburg County.; Local government records -- Virginia -- Lunenburg County.; Marriage records -- Virginia -- Lunenburg County.; Probate accounts -- Virginia -- Lunenburg County.; Wills -- Virginia -- Lunenburg County.
Contents List
- Unrecorded Wills, etc. 1743-1926 (Barcode 1012168)
- Wills, 1746-1759 (Barcode 1012167)
- Wills, Inventories, etc., 1760-1774 (Barcode 1177168)
- Wills, Inventories, Accounts, Marriage Lists, etc., 1775-1785 (Barcode 1177167)
- Wills, Inventories, Accounts, Marriage Lists, etc., 1786-1795 (Barcode 1177166)
- Wills, Inventories, Accounts, Marriage Lists, etc., 1796-1801 (Barcode 1177165)
- Wills, Inventories, Accounts, Marriage Lists, etc., 1802-1805 (Barcode 1177164)
- Wills, Inventories, Accounts, Marriage Lists, etc., 1806-1810 (Barcode 1177163)
- Wills, Inventories, Accounts, Marriage Lists, etc., 1811-1814 (Barcode 1177153)
- Wills, Inventories, Accounts, Marriage Lists, etc., 1815-1818 (Barcode 1177154)
- Wills, Inventories, Accounts, Marriage Lists, etc., 1819-1821 (Barcode 1177155)
- Wills, Inventories, Accounts, Marriage Lists, etc., 1822-1824 (Barcode 1177156)
- Wills, Inventories, Accounts, Marriage Lists, etc., 1825-1826 (Barcode 1177157)
- Wills, Inventories, Accounts, Marriage Lists, etc., 1826-1827 (Barcode 1177158)
- Wills, Inventories, Accounts, Marriage Lists, etc., 1828-1829 (Barcode 1177159)
- Wills, Inventories, Accounts, Marriage Lists, etc., 1829-1830 (Barcode 1177160)
- Wills, Inventories, Accounts, Marriage Lists, etc., 1830-1832 (Barcode 1177161)
- Wills, Inventories, Accounts, Marriage Lists, etc., 1833-1835 (Barcode 1177162)
- Wills, Inventories, Accounts, Marriage Lists, etc., 1836-1838 (Barcode 1177656)
- Wills, Inventories, Accounts, Marriage Lists, etc., 1838-1841 (Barcode 1177657)
- Wills, Inventories, Accounts, Marriage Lists, etc., 1842-1845 (Barcode 1177658)
- Wills, Inventories, Accounts, Fiduciary Bonds filed in Circuit Superior Court and Circuit Court, 1842-1888 (Barcode 1175966)
- Wills, Inventories, Accounts, Marriage Lists, etc., 1845-1848 (Barcode 1177659)
- Wills, Inventories, Accounts, Marriage Lists, etc., 1848-1851 (Barcode 1177664)
- Wills, 1852-1872 (Barcode 1177660)
- Wills, 1873-1906 (Barcode 1177661)
- Wills, 1907-1919 (Barcode 1177662)
- Wills, 1920-1928 (Barcode 1177663)
- Oversize Wills, Inventories, Accounts, Marriage Lists, etc., 1764-1915 (Barcode 1175967)